Shubham Satish Gadgil

Cloud Devops Engineer

Phone -+358 465896130 / +91 8975108188

Location - Helsinki, Finland

Mail – <u>ShubhamGadgil@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin- https://www.linkedin.com/in/shubham-gadgil-4886a096

Career Objective – Keep Learning Keep Growing

Intend to build a career in a leading corporate environment that gives ample scope to utilize my skills, apply my knowledge and contribute my service to the organization success with challenging & creative opportunities

Having **6.5+ years of experience in IT industry** and currently working in leading IT organization Tata Consultancy Services with designation IT Analyst.



SKILLS

Cloud Platform: Private cloud services, AWS

Continuous Deployment (CI/CD): Github, Bitbucket, Jenkins, Maven, Sonarqube,

Artifactory, Nolio Release Automation, ArgoCD

Infrastructure as Code: Terraform, CloudFormation

Configuration Management: Ansible

Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes, Amazon ECS, Amazon EKS

Monitoring and Logging: Dynatrace, Prometheus, Grafana, CloudWatch, Solarwinds

Scripting and Automation: Bash, PowerShell, Ignio Automation tool

Version Control Systems: Git, SVN

Networking: TCP/IP, DNS, VPN, Load Balancers, HAProxy

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS, RHEL), Windows Server, AIX, HP-UX

Security: Identity and Access Management (IAM), Security Groups, Encryption, Hashicorp Vault

Middleware: Jboss, Weblogic, Apache Tomcat, Apache Http, Nginx, Iplanet, IBM MQ, Apache ActiveMQ,

Tibco BW, Tibco EMS

Other Tools: BMC Control-M, Jira, Servicenow, HPSM



Work Experience / Projects

Oct 2016 to Current - Tata Consultancy Services, Pune, India

Project 1: Postnord AB, Sweden (Oct 2016 to May 2018)

Location: Pune, Maharashtra

Description: Logistic / Postal services (Support and Maintenance)

Role: System Engineer

Project 2: Bonnier AB, Sweden (Jun 2018 to April 2019)

Location: Pune, Maharashtra

Description: Media Group (Datacenter Migration and Transformation)

Role: Integration Engineer

Project 3: OP Bank, Finland (May 2019 to Current)

Location: Helsinki, Finland

Description: Banking and Finance (Datacenter Migration and Transformation)

Role: Cloud Engineer

- Performed Application Migration DC to DC with Rehosting and Replatforming strategies in Private cloud.
- Engineered end-to-end application refactoring of a legacy system, including networking, DNS management, installation, configuration, integration, deployment, security, and monitoring; reduced system downtime and boosted performance.
- Integrated Applications with various Databases, web server, MQ, other systems
- Designed and implemented scalable cloud infrastructure solutions in on-prem private cloud.
- Developed automation scripts in Bash, Powershell, Control-m batch and automation tools like Ignio to streamline deployment processes, Routine operations resulting in saving time and manual efforts.
- Implemented Platform and Application upgrade for Critical Banking applications
- Automated Software development lifecycle with deploying CI/CD pipelines using Git, Jenkins, Nolio deployer and ArgoCD to enabling automated builds, tests, and deployments for multiple applications.
- Managed containerization technologies like Docker and Kubernetes to deploy microservices architecture and achieve improved scalability and resource utilization.
- Monitored and maintained system performance using Dynatrace, Prometheus, Grafana, Solarwinds ensuring high availability and proactive issue resolution.
- Maintained version control systems (Git/SVN) for source code management and collaborated with development teams to establish effective branching and merging strategies.
- Worked closely with the security team to implement security best practices, conduct regular audits, and enforce compliance with industry standards.
- Provided crendentials management solution using Hashicorp Vault.
- Developed Solutions, Troubleshoot, Tested & Monitored applications to identify potential bottlenecks, Performance analysis and collaborate with stakeholders on solution implementation.
- Worked closely with customers, internal teams and stakeholders to determine, planning, implementation and integration of system-oriented/migration projects.
- Implemeted POC's on AWS EC2,IAM,S3,VPC,Route53,ELB, EKS,ECS,Cloud watch etc.



Education

May 2016 - Bachelor of Engineer (E&TC) From – Savitribai Phule, Pune University, Maharashtra, India



Certifications

Dec 2017 Microsoft Azure (laas) (Internal)
May 2018 Certified ITIL practitioner (Axelos)

June 2019 BMC Control-M Fundamental Scheduling (BMC)

Dec 2022 Docker (Internal)

Dec 2023 Certified Kubernetes Administration (Linux Foundation)



Interests

Public Clouds DevOps

Microservices



Personal Details

Nationality: Indian

Passport : Indian (N5131735)
Languages : English, Hindi, Marathi

Visa: Finnish Residence Permit, Valid till – 23rd Dec 2023

Current Location: Helsinki, Finland

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my belief.